Guide to the Carolyn S. Schumacher Papers AIS.2011.09
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Carolyn S. Schumacher Papers
1883-2008
1968-1988
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Schumacher, Carolyn S.
AIS.2011.09
7.5 Linear Feet (9 boxes)
These papers document the career of historian and archivist Dr. Carolyn S. Schumacher, including materials related to her research and activism in Pittsburgh, Pa., specifically related to corporal punishment in schools, educational history, women's history, and archives.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Carolyn S. Schumacher in September 2011 (Series I-V). Additional material was received in 2012 (Series VI-VIII).
Arrangement
The Carolyn S. Schumacher Papers are arranged in eight series:
Series I. Corporal Punishment in Schools
Series II. Pittsburgh Public Schools Archival Project
Series III. Pittsburgh Schools Research File
Series IV. History of College Women in Pittsburgh Research File
Series V. Legal File
Series VI. Women at Pitt Research File
Series VII. "The History of Women at Pitt: Reflections on a Changing Society" Exhibit
Series VIII. Women in Higher Education
Biography
Carolyn Sutcher Schumacher graduated from South Shore Public High School in Chicago, Illinois, in January 1951 and began studies in liberal arts at the University of Wisconsin, Madison. In January 1953, she transferred to the University of Illinois at Urbana and graduated with a Bachelor of Science in Education in August 1954. She completed a Master's degree in History at the University of Washington (Seattle) in June 1956 and moved to Pittsburgh to begin a career in teaching in the Pittsburgh Public Schools at the Spring Garden Elementary School in 1957. She later began her doctoral studies in History at the University of Pittsburgh in September 1969. Her dissertation, School Attendance in Nineteenth Century Pittsburgh: Wealth, Ethnicity and Occupational Mobility of School Age Children, 1855-1865 was completed in 1977 under the direction of Dr. Samuel P. Hays.
Following her employment with the Pittsburgh Public Schools, Dr. Schumacher held positions as a curriculum writer at the University of Pittsburgh, worked in Carnegie Mellon University's history department and was also the administrative director of the Archives, Museum, and Editing program at Duquesne University.
Dr. Schumacher was professionally active with local and national organizations, including the American Civil Liberties Union, in an attempt to abolish corporal punishment in schools. She held membership in the American Historical Association, the Organization of American Historians, History of Education Society, and the Coordinating Committee on Women in the Historical Professions. She was also a founding member of the National Committee to Abolish Corporal Punishment in Schools, a chairperson for the Pittsburgh Committee for the Abolition of Corporal Punishment in Public Schools, and a board member of the Pittsburgh Chapter American Civil Liberties Union.
Dr. Schumacher received a $3,000 grant from the H.C. Frick Educational Commission for a 15-month records survey of the Pittsburgh Public Schools and became the director of the Pittsburgh Public Schools Archival Project. Her perspective on the project was published in an article in entitled, "Using Board of Education Materials for Local History," which appeared in the Western Pennsylvania Historical Magazine, in January 1983. Following her work on the records survey she held positions at the Frick Art and Historical Center and at the Historical Society of Western Pennsylvania, where she became the director of the Library and Archives Division in 1990. She was with the Historical Society when it opened the Senator John Heinz Pittsburgh Regional History Center in 1996 and retired from professional activity in 1998.
Previous Citation
Carolyn S. Schumacher Papers, 1883-2008, AIS.2011.09, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Scope and Content Notes
The Carolyn S. Schumacher Papers contain materials related to Schumacher's research and activism. The research materials include many historical and contemporary articles that have been photocopied from published sources. Additionally, there are bibliographies, oral histories on cassette tapes, conference proceedings, contracts, correspondence, directories, legislation, lists, meeting minutes, newsletters, newspaper clippings, notes, and presentation materials.
Related Material
Pittsburgh School District Records, 1836-1937, AIS.1969.18, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Cathryn Irvis Papers, 1978-1980, AIS.2006.02, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
East End Education Committee Records, 1969-1972, AIS.1993.01, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Pittsburgh Board of Public Education (Pa.); Corporal punishment of children; Education; Women; Archival surveys; Children's rights; Women -- Education (Higher) -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Associations; University of Pittsburgh; Public schools -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- History; Social action; Schumacher, Carolyn S.
- Corporal Punishment in Schools, 1965-2008; 1968-1980; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Series I contains materials related to Schumacher's activism in and research on local and national initiatives to end corporal punishment in schools. Series includes articles, conference proceedings, correspondence, legislation, meeting minutes, newsletters, notes, publications, and speeches.
  - National Committee to Abolish Corporal Punishment Schools, 1965-1982; 1.
    The National Committee to Abolish Corporal Punishment subseries contains materials related to Schumacher's activism in this national organization, that aimed to end corporal punishment in schools. Subseries includes articles, conference proceedings, correspondence, legislation, meeting minutes, newsletters, notes, publications, and speeches.
    - ACLU- Arlene Richards, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - ACLU on Corporal Punishment, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - ACLU on Corporal Punishment, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - ACLU Expulsion, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - ACLU Newsletter, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - ACLU- Reitman, Hyman, Foster, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - ACLU Student Rights, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Adam Maurer (EVAN-G, End Violence Against the Next Generation, Berkeley, CA), 1972-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Alan Reitman, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Alan Reitman (ACLU), 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - American Psychological Association Task Force on Rights of Children and Youth, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bernstein and Glinn, Atlanta, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Board of Directors- Reply, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Board Members- Letters, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Child Abuse: Where Do We Go From Here? Conference Proceedings and Conference on Corporal Punishment in the Schools: A National Debate, 1977 February 18-20 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Committee List, circa 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Committee Names, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Conference on Discipline and Violence in School and Society, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Corporal Punishment Advisory Board, 1979 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Corporal Punishment Advisory Board, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Corporal Punishment Board, 1976 December 5 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Corporal Punishment Correspondence, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Corporal Punishment "Discipline", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Corporal Punishment, or Something You Can Do To Student But Not to Soldiers, Sailors, Prisoners, or Servants, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Corporal Punishment Stationary, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - David Harrison (American Civil Liberties Union of Vermont), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Dr. Herbert L. Foster (SUNY Buffalo), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Dr. Irwin A. Hyman (Temple University), 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Duncan, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Foundations and Rejections, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Foundation Request Responses, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Frances Castan (Editor of Scholastic Teacher magazine), 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Freedom News, Council of Federated Organizations, circa 1965 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Gerald Foulds- Attorney General Office, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Herbert Foster (Professor of Education, SUNY Buffalo), 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Ingraham vs. Wright, Supreme County, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Minutes, June 1975 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - National Center Corporal Punishment, Correspondence, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - National Committee to Abolish Corporal Punishment in Schools, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - National Committee to Abolish Corporal Punishment in Schools, Letters, Rejection Board, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - NCACP, 1973 May (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - NCACP, 1973 June (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - NCACP Board Meeting, 1974 June (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - NCACP- Letters- Acceptance Board, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - NCACP Meeting, 1975 June 25 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - NCACP Minutes, 1976 January 14 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - NCACP, Miscellaneous, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - NCACP Newsletter Perspective, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Nat Hentoff, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Newsletter Copy, Strike Three, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Peter Schrag, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Philip Hallen, Falk Medical Fund, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Reitman Speech, American Psychological Association, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Richard Sussman, National Committee to Abolish Corporal Punishment in Schools, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Subscriptions Sent to NCACPs, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Supreme Court, Corporal Punishment, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Temple University, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Testimony of Dr. David Gil (Brandeis University), 1973 March 26 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Local Corporal Punishment Issues, 1966-1980; 2.
    The Local Corporal Punishment Issues subseries contains materials related to Schumacher's activism in the National Committee to Abolish Corporal Punishment at the local level, primarily in the Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania region. The subseries includes articles, conference proceedings, correspondence, legislation, meeting minutes, newsletters, notes, publications, and speeches.
    - Address Lists, 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Blackout CP Cases, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Board of Education, Pittsburgh, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Board of Education Notes, 1975 October 16 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Board of Education Open Hearing, 1976 February-March (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - CACP Correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Children's Lobby of Western PA, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Corporal Punishment- Local, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Corporal Punishment in Washington School between 1873-1896, undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Dr. Sidney P. Maryland Jr (Superintendent of Pittsburgh Public Schools), 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - East End Education Committee, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Elected School Board, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - House Bill 786, PA General Assembly, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Informed Consent- Pittsburgh Public Schools, undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - New Kensington NACAP, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Pennsylvania Association for Retarded Children, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Pennsylvania Department of Welfare- Child Abuse, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Pennsylvania Education, Corporal Punishment, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Pennsylvania State School Code, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Pittsburgh Area Preschool Association (P.A.P.A.), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Pittsburgh Board of Education, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Pittsburgh Board of Education, 1975 October (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Pittsburgh Board of Education, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Pittsburgh Corporal Punishment, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Pittsburgh Council on Public Education (PCPE), 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Pittsburgh Elected School Board, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Pittsburgh Public Schools, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Pittsburgh School Board, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Pittsburgh School Board Meeting, 1975 November 18 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Reizenstein, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Senate 544- Jerry Colson Statement, PA General Assembly, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Short Article to Pittsburgh Magazine, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Staff Papers Submitted to Frank Beals' Committee, 1970 April 27 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Surveys, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Research on Corporal Punishment, 1967-2008; 3.
    The Research on Corporal Punishment subseries contains materials related to Schumacher's research in corporal punishment both in homes and schools in the United States and abroad. The subseries includes articles, conference proceedings, correspondence, newsletters, notes, publications, and studies.
    - Biennial Women's Study, Philadelphia, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Book Reviews, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Children's Rights, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Cindy Waraks, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Corporal Punishment Articles, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Corporal Punishment Articles by Schumacher, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Corporal Punishment Bibliography, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - "Corporal Punishment" by Herbert Falk 1941, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Corporal Punishment Materials, 1977-1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Corporal Punishment Materials, 1998-2008 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Corporal Punishment Study in England published in 1952, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - David Campbell (University of Pittsburgh), 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Desegregation, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Dick Warner (Wisconsin Case), 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Elementary Secondary Education Act (ESEA), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - England, Household Violence, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Extra Copy of Corporal Punishment Survey by Stuart Shaffer, Ph.D., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Family Violence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Food, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Fred Speaker (Writer, Education Pennsylvania), 1975 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - James Holland, UPitt Course, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Schumacher Articles for Publication, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Tom Watman (Watman Educational Services, Henniker, TN), 1973 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - United Mental Health, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Young Men and Women's Hebrew Association, Funtime Kiddieland Camp, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Intercultural Education through Art and Music, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - University of Pennsylvania Law Review, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Pittsburgh Public Schools Archival Project, 1966-1984; 1981-1983; II.
  Series II contains materials related to the Pittsburgh Public Schools Archival Project directed by Carolyn S. Schumacher in 1981-1982. It includes correspondence, newspaper clippings, proposals, reports, and research notes related to this project.
  - Correspondence & Contracts, 1978-1983; 1981-1982; 1.
    The Correspondence & Contracts subseries contains materials related to the Pittsburgh Public Schools Archival Project directed by Schumacher in 1981-1982. It includes correspondence, such as letters, memos, and address information, as well as contracts between Schumacher and a variety of organizations.
    - Board Members Addresses, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Contracts, 1981 December 14 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Contracts with Board of Education, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence with Mike Murphy, University of Western Ontario, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence with Teachers, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Donors Correspondence, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Frick Commission Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - General Memos, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Information Service Memos, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Internal Memos, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Introductory Letters to Principals, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Kodak Eastman Correspondence, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Letter from Frank Zabrosky, UPitt AIS, Regarding School Records, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Letters to Board Members, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Memos from Aldo Colautti, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Memos to Mr. Rifugiato, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Memos to Superintendent, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Mr. Linder- Arsenal Middle School, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Original Letter Regarding Survey, from Curtis Walker, Office of Deputy Superintendent, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - People to Consult in Schools, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - People Who Received Archives Materials and Final Reports, 1983 January (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Principal Assignments/ Retired Personnel, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Reference Correspondence, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Publications, Proposals, & Reports, 1966-1984; 1981-1982
    The Publications, Proposals, & Reports subseries contains materials related to the Pittsburgh Public Schools Archival Project directed by Schumacher in 1981-1982. It includes articles, drafts, notes, reports, proposals, summaries, and surveys related to this project.
    - Archives Alpha Master, with Introduction, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Draft Report on Preliminary Survey, 1981 December 30 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Draft Report to Frick Commission, 1981 December 30 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Final Report, Introduction Only, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Final Report Master, 1982 December 31 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Final Report, Preliminary Survey of School Records and Archival Materials, Pittsburgh Public Schools, Oct. 1- Dec. 31, 1981, 1982 February 1 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Final Report, Preliminary Survey of School Records and Archival Materials, Pittsburgh Public Schools, Oct. 1- Dec. 31, 1981, Abbreviated Version, 1982 February 1 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - First Draft Report/Recommendation to Superintendent, 1982 April 1 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Great High Schools, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Master 1 and 2 for Final Report, circa 1981 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - The News from Pittsburgh Public Schools, December 1982 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Newspaper Article, "City Schools' Nooks, Crannies Yield Dusty Look into Past", 1981 November (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Notes for Final Report, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Pittsburgh Public Schools Archives Brochures, 1982 June- October (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Posters for Slideshow, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Preliminary Proposal, 1981 September 10 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Proposal Jan. 1, 1982- Dec. 21, 1982, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Report to Superintendent, 1982 April 1 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - "Reporter" Conroy Sheltered Workshop, 1982 March 15 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Sample Final Reports for Frick, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Schoolhouse Beautiful Article, with Slides, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Set, Finished and Xeroxed, circa 1981 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Summary Report, 1981 December 14 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Summary Report, 1981 December 15 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Summary of Space Estimate for Preliminary Inventory, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Superintendent Misc., 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Survey Proposal, 1981 September 22 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Survey of School Records and Archival Materials, Pittsburgh Public Schools, Mid Year Report, 1982 July 12 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - "Using Board of Education Materials for Local History," by C. Schumacher, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Research, 1970-1983; 1981-1983
    The Research subseries contains materials related to the Pittsburgh Public Schools Archival Project directed by Schumacher in 1981-1982. It includes articles, floor plans, inventories, lists, and photographs related to this project.
    - Conservation Techniques and Storage, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Floor Plan, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - List of Inventories, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Master Xerox Inventories, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Pittsburgh School District Records Inventory, circa 1970 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - School List Master, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - School Photographs, Negatives, and Slides, circa 1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Schools with Blue Histories, circa 1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Pittsburgh Schools Research File, 1921-2001; 1978-1983; III.
  Series III contains materials related to Schumacher's research about the Pittsburgh Schools in the late nineteenth and twentieth centuries, including curriculum and testing, the buildings, teachers and students, discipline methods, and records. It includes articles and publications (many of which are photocopies), bibliographies, correspondence, directories, newspaper clippings, and notes.
  - Allegheny City, circa 1980; 1.
    The Allegheny City subseries contains materials related to Schumacher's research about the Allegheny City school system in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries, including photocopies of primary materials and notes.
    - Allegheny Board of Controllers 1894-1900 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Allegheny Board Minutes- Attendance 1896-1900 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Allegheny Board Minutes- Compulsory Education 1896-1900 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Allegheny Board Minutes- Cost of Free Text Books 1896-1900 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Allegheny Board Minutes- High School Program 1895-1900 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Allegheny Board Minutes- Truant School 1896-1900 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Allegheny City Schools, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Allegheny City Board of Controllers Committee, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Allegheny Teacher Salaries 1901(copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Allegheny Ward 9 Minutes 1897- 1911 Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Allegheny Wards/Schools, circa 1982 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Articles & Photocopies, 1921-1984; 2.
    The Articles & Photocopies subseries contains primarily articles and publications that have been photocopied for Schumacher's research about the Pittsburgh Schools in the late nineteenth and twentieth centuries, including its curriculum, education reform, testing, classrooms and school buidlings, statistics about teachers and students, discipline methods, and school records.
    - Age of High Schools Students in 1882 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - 1885 Alumni Annuals (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Arsenal Technical School, Indianapolis, IN, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - 1873 Attendance (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - A Brief History of Pittsburgh by Mrs. Edward Jones, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - 1913-1933 Building Plans (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Census Literacy 1870-1969, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Census Printed 1850 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Census Printed 1860 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Census Printed 1880 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Census Printed 1910 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Census Printed 1920 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Classroom Discipline by Stoops and Dunworth, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Census Printed 1940, includes 1890-1940 Table (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Cleveland Report 1914 (copy), undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Committee on Pittsburgh Archaeology and History- Thomas Baker, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - David Angus Publications, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 30)